<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="1.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Revolution blahg</title>
        <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/</link>
        <description>mapleoin's rambling blahg</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 12:37:51 +0300</pubDate>
        <generator>pyBlee!</generator>
        <item>
            <title>The Productive Programmer</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/productive-programmer-review</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description> &lt;div style="float: left; padding: 1em"&gt;
&lt;img src="/covers/productive.jpg" style="text-align:left;" alt="" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I read &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596519788?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpmapleoinb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0596519788"&gt;The Productive Programmer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve already got a bunch of books piled up and waiting to be read, some of which I&amp;#8217;ve reached the middle of and some of which I&amp;#8217;ve read only the introduction to. I was bored today and this looked like an easy read that I could drop at any time. It is an easy read, but the fact is, it&amp;#8217;s very catchy. It draws you in and doesn&amp;#8217;t want to be let go. It&amp;#8217;s a great way to spend half a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could have been another one of those &amp;#8220;94 things you need to know&amp;#8221; books, but I think this title is way better. The tips are divided into 2 big sections and a few separate chapters within each one, giving the book some structure. One of the strange things about it is that its advice spans across 3 different platforms (*nix, OS X and Windows) and they&amp;#8217;re all mingled together in the same chapter. I was put off by this at first, but after I&amp;#8217;d gotten into the book a bit I realized that it is, in fact, a good idea. The whole theme of the book is programmer productivity and the reason it has this title and not a cheesy title with numbers like &amp;#8220;94.3 productivity tips for programmers&amp;#8221; is that the tips aren&amp;#8217;t what&amp;#8217;s important. The book is there to hit people in the head with and open their minds. You aren&amp;#8217;t supposed to just use the tips provided, that&amp;#8217;s unimportant. What&amp;#8217;s important is that you have a shock and realize that you&amp;#8217;ve been the wrong kind of lazy as a programmer. You&amp;#8217;ve stopped automating, you&amp;#8217;ve become a machine; in the author&amp;#8217;s own words, computers have started &amp;#8220;getting together late at night to make fun of their users&amp;#8221;. As soon as I realized what this book was really about, I started reading the Windows tips as well. I also stopped a few times to look in my distro&amp;#8217;s repository for tools that I had known of, but never used before, only now understanding their true purpose. There are many applications that seem just trendy at first, until you realize that even a small productivity boost is a big productivity boost. (Go check out &amp;#8220;gnome-do&amp;#8221;, I&amp;#8217;d heard about it years ago, but never tried it until now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book contains tips ranging from application launchers, Firefox&amp;#8217;s magic address bar, bash scripting commands to office productivity tips for killing distractions. Once again, the mindset is important, not the tips themselves. The big take-away from this book is beginning to constantly judge everything you do as a programmer. This isn&amp;#8217;t new advice (at least for those who have read &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/020161622X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpmapleoinb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=020161622X"&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/a&gt; , which by the way is mentioned several times in this book), but I find it&amp;#8217;s better emphasized in this book. At one point in the book, the author explains how it took his team one hour to devise a Ruby script to automate some simple task that would&amp;#8217;ve required 10 minutes if done manually and finally only needed doing 5 times. One could say there was a loss in productivity, but as the author points out, one would be wrong. Those 50 minutes would&amp;#8217;ve been spent with the brain turned off, whereas the hour writing the script was spent &lt;strong&gt;learning&lt;/strong&gt;, focusing, practicing, gaining knowledge that can later be used on a different project. Some of us would probably have gotten bored in those 50 minutes and fallen into procrastination. That doesn&amp;#8217;t happen when you&amp;#8217;ve got a complex problem to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the first part of the book, &lt;em&gt;Mechanics&lt;/em&gt;. The second part, &lt;em&gt;Practice&lt;/em&gt; is a bit harder to read, as it&amp;#8217;s not just disparaged tips on very different applications. They&amp;#8217;re quite two separate books actually. The majority of the examples in Part IIare java (they&amp;#8217;re mostly readable even for someone who doesn&amp;#8217;t speak the exact dialect of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOP&lt;/span&gt; that java uses) and this part is mostly about software &lt;strong&gt;construction&lt;/strong&gt; as &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735619670?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpmapleoinb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735619670"&gt;Steve McConnell&lt;/a&gt; would say, but it&amp;#8217;s also about Java. I learned a new acronym: &lt;acronym title="You Ain’t Gonna Need It"&gt;YAGNI&lt;/acronym&gt; which basically means that thinking ahead is bad. This is probably one of the advices that I feel the least guilty about, but which I sometime observe in people around me. Never program a feature you don&amp;#8217;t urgently have a need for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the good points of this book is the originality with which the ideas are expressed. Most of these ideas aren&amp;#8217;t new, especially to anyone who&amp;#8217;s read other software engineering books. The text is spiced up with little narratives of different adventures from the author&amp;#8217;s experience as a consultant and there is also an &lt;strong&gt;Ancient Philosophers&lt;/strong&gt; chapter and an explanation of the PacMan game&amp;#8217;s way of functioning (although I didn&amp;#8217;t understand how that&amp;#8217;s supposed to make the game less enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 02:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Beginning Packaging for Fedora</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/packaging-for-fedora</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;With &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSOC&lt;/span&gt; now over, which I should write a blogpost about soon, I&amp;#8217;ve taken a break from pkgdb and web programming and started developing another skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that &lt;a href="https://admin.fedoraproject.org/pkgdb/users/packages/mapleoin"&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; is empty has been bugging me for too much time, so I set out to fix it. I also wanted to find out more about the packaging process and the road of a package before it gets accepted into fedora&amp;#8217;s official repos which is a bit complex. This knowledge would also help me better understand the parts of pkgdb which packagers interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not my first time trying to make a package for fedora. I think this is actually my third time. I&amp;#8217;d given up before, scared by all the different tools and scattered documentation. In a previous life, I had made some &lt;a href="http://aur.archlinux.org/"&gt;AUR&lt;/a&gt; packages, but the experience is a lot different. I&amp;#8217;m now starting to get used to all the different tools that I was scared of before, like mock and rpmlint and I can now find my way around the fedora wiki for package related information. There is a wealth of information in the wiki, but you need a lot of patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started slow, with quite a complex application to package: &lt;a href="http://calibre.kovidgoyal.net/"&gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt; . Having all those different distros is great when you&amp;#8217;re a packager, because you have somewhere to look for help and the Debian package of calibre helped me a lot. It took me about two days to get a somewhat acceptable version of calibre packaged, which I then posted to redhat&amp;#8217;s bugzilla. The following days I found more small apps to be packaged and it became easier and easier for me to do it. Last night for example, I was just browsing &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.org"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; as usual when I found a link to &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/news.php?blog=1&amp;amp;story=301"&gt;facebook&amp;#8217;s opensourcing of their web server framework&lt;/a&gt; I just rushed to the download and installation instructions page and I quickly got it packaged. I&amp;#8217;m not saying it&amp;#8217;s perfect, it probably needs a lot of improvement, but it was fun to do. It&amp;#8217;s fun to think that you&amp;#8217;re making things easier for someone and learning a lot at the same time. I now have 5 packages waiting to be reviewed and I&amp;#8217;ve found someone willing to sponsor me into the &lt;em&gt;packager&lt;/em&gt; group. Anyone in a package-review mood? ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey into the packaging world has been enlightening so far and the good thing is I&amp;#8217;m just beginning. There&amp;#8217;s a whole new world to be discovered out there and also another part of the fedora community. &lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 11:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Emacs la Ceata</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/emacs-in-ceata</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;Să folosesc blogul ăsta și altfel decât până acum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dacă mă are cineva în feed reader și vrea să meargă la o mică (o juma&amp;#8217; de duzină de oameni) prezentare emacs în politehnică, cu oamenii din &lt;a href="http://ceata.org"&gt;Ceata&lt;/a&gt; (probabil e stricat situl în momentul ăsta), știți cum să mă contactați. Întâlnirea va avea loc mâine probabil după ora 18 în sediul Cetei din unul din căminele din Poli.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ceata e o organizație de studenți din Politehnică interesați de tehnologii libere.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 19:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>FUDCon Berlin</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/fudcon-berlin</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;I just got back from this year&amp;#8217;s &lt;acronym title="Europe, the Middle East and Africa"&gt;EMEA&lt;/acronym&gt; &lt;acronym title="Fedora Users and Developers Conference"&gt;FUDCON&lt;/acronym&gt; in Berlin with &lt;a href="http://nicubunu.blogspot.com"&gt;Nicu&lt;/a&gt; . I didn&amp;#8217;t have time to write anything while I was there because so much was happening all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://fedora.nicubunu.ro/photos/fudcon2009berlin/613-img_1477.jpg.medium.jpeg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;FUDCon and LinuxTag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinuxTag wasn&amp;#8217;t really the purpose of our visit, but we got free tickets so I checked the place out for a while. There were lots of booths and some speeches (mostly in German). There were also some activities, but I really didn&amp;#8217;t get to any of them since most appeared to be German-only. I was a bit disappointed, &lt;a href="http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/eLiberatica-aftermath"&gt;eLiberatica&lt;/a&gt; had way better talks and guests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FUDCon was nice. The first day was a little slow to start, but the BarCamp session the next day was very interesting and diverse. More of that would&amp;#8217;ve been nice. Some of the cool topics I enjoyed were: koji at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CERN&lt;/span&gt;, git for hackers, Fedora &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EKG&lt;/span&gt; and UI Design. The last day was mostly random hacking by people who already had something to work on. I did a bit of pkgdb hacking on my own and then went Berlinxploring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Berlin&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city was awesome. I haven&amp;#8217;t been to a lot of different countries, but right now Berlin is my favourite. Its public transportation is awesome, the people are polite, friendly and everyone can speak English. There were a lot of trees everywhere, the temperature was really cool and there were wild bunnies in the parks! I separated from the crowd two times to go visit the city and I got to see some stuff I would&amp;#8217;ve missed otherwise. It was also cool because what I did was basically ride the train and get off whenever I would see something interesting. I went to the Brandenburg gate and the Governmental district and also got a closer look of the bombed church. I also went to a cool flea market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;German Beer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of the whole conference were the nights out at the restaurant, I think. I and Nicu were lucky to tag along to a few people from Red Hat before the majority of people had arrived. We got to see some nice places that way, especially thanks to Jesse&amp;#8217;s iphone. I got to eat indian food, assembly line sushy and we were also at the local Zoo. I soon found out that my English was a bit slow and so I couldn&amp;#8217;t keep up with their constant witty joking so I sort of gave up and switched into listening mode.&lt;br /&gt;The nights-at-the-restaurant got better and better as more people arrived. We went to a small restaurant right under the railways for free pizza (thanks Red Hat!) where I met a few of the newly arrived people and had some interesting chats mostly about fedora and Red Hat.&lt;br /&gt;The next day we went looking for a Sudanese restaurant, but ended up at a Cuban restaurant with cool waitresses. I got to taste the first real German beer and socialised with some of the other European guys which was really fun. &lt;br /&gt;The last night was the best night. We had interesting discussions about fonetics(!), German beer, the Dutch language and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RMS&lt;/span&gt; among other things. They also had the greatest dark German beer, which I forgot the name of. Real traditional German beer really doesn&amp;#8217;t compare with any other beer. It&amp;#8217;s a whole different beverage and an awesome one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I think it was a great experience. I got to meet a lot of interesting and smart people from all over the world who all shared a passion for their work and for Fedora.&lt;br /&gt;So these are sort of the words to &lt;a href="http://fedora.nicubunu.ro/photos/fudcon2009berlin/"&gt;Nicu&amp;#8217;s photos&lt;/a&gt; which explain the rest, only better.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 20:20 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>eLiberatica - the aftermath!</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/eLiberatica-aftermath</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;Wow, what an event! It was way more awesome than I expected. This is probably one of the later posts to get to the planet from eLiberatica because I wanted to form a complete opinion on the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;eLiberatica is the first big open source and free software conference I&amp;#8217;ve been to. The scale of it is quite amazing for something this far East in Europe and especially for my country. Some high-profile guest even said that he was astonished at the presence of very influential, key &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FLOSS&lt;/span&gt; personalities that aren&amp;#8217;t present at some bigger events.&lt;br /&gt;the booths&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (&lt;a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/User:Ajoian"&gt;ajoian&lt;/a&gt; , &lt;a href="http://nicubunu.ro"&gt;nicubunu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://alexxed.com"&gt;alexxed&lt;/a&gt; and myself) had a whole booth for fedora and we really made the best of that opportunity, I think. We had a lot of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SWAG&lt;/span&gt;. Nicu had printed some posters for the event which really helped beautify the booth and had also printed some fedora business cards for each of us. We had fedora t-shirts and a lot of CDs sent by Max (thanks Max!). These were the most helpful for starting conversations with passers-by. We even helped out the Ubuntu people when they ran out of cds on the first day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.fedoraproject.ro/files/dsc03883.resized_0.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The booth activity was more fun than I had expected. I didn&amp;#8217;t think I would enjoy talking to people about fedora so much. We had people ask us to come to their town and “do something about fedora”. We told them we&amp;#8217;d come and hold presentations when they would be ready and we gave them some free LiveCDs to spread around in the meantime. I hope we&amp;#8217;ll have some new local fedora communities spring up. I&amp;#8217;m especially hopeful of the guys from Iași who are active contributors to different opensource projects, mostly xwiki .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two other cool booths that were very engaging with the passers-by: the Mozilla booth and the Romanian Free Software Communities booth which was more of an Ubuntu booth actually, but that was good since a lot of people were interested in that.&lt;br /&gt;the speakers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only went to a few speeches as the booth activity and the new people I met were too engaging. I think Jeroen‘s speech was awesome and his message was very clear. It was a great complement to the discourse we were holding at the booth – telling people that fedora is all about contributing, not just using a stable, already tested linux distribution. A lot of people were ubuntu users, especially the ones in the Politehnica University (the host of the event) who are taught Ubuntu in class (there are no linux machines at my university :| ). Everyone kept asking how fedora is better than ubuntu. It was an honest question since many of them didn&amp;#8217;t have experience anything else and I hope we succeeded in getting our message accross.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were other awesome people, too. There was Monty – the founder of MySQL who told us about his new project to give MySQL back to the community: MariaDB . There was the president of fsfe and the OpenSource Diva – Danesse Cooper who both gave great philosophical speeches. There was David Axmark who had a great presentation about his awesome new project to create a stripped-down version of MySQL for webshops called Drizzle – I think this will be a great project to watch evolve. I didn&amp;#8217;t get to spend too much time on the openagile track, but I went to Corey Haines ‘s talk about software craftsmanship in an agile context which I enjoyed.&lt;br /&gt;the friends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;contributors&lt;br /&gt;The most awesome part of the entire conference, I think, were the people I met. There were a lot of people I only knew from online discussions. Some of them I had known for years, but had never met. I had a revelation with a couple of people who I didn&amp;#8217;t like online, but prooved to be very nice people in real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met some fellow Romanian Google Summer of Code guys for this year and last year with whom I hope to meet again.&lt;br /&gt;I met a few Eau de Web guys – a small python/zope web company especially Alex who&amp;#8217;s blog I had been reading and who turned out to be an even cooler guy than I expected. We discussed a lot of interesting python things. (I almost got him to switch from his OS X + virtual Debian setup to fedora. But I hope I&amp;#8217;ll have another swing at it soon).&lt;br /&gt;I met an old friend, Vlad who gave me an awesome idea for an enhancement to the fedora business cards that I&amp;#8217;ll hopefully have time to implement this summer.&lt;br /&gt;The guys from the other Romanian communities were cool people and I hope we&amp;#8217;ll interact better and do more awesome &lt;span class="caps"&gt;FLOSS&lt;/span&gt; stuff now that we&amp;#8217;ve met face to face. These were people from Software Liber, rosedu and the cool lonely guy from openSUSE Romania who had a taste of our fedora CDs, &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/nicubunu/3558623559/"&gt;literally&lt;/a&gt; (the opensuse community is just starting out in Romania).&lt;br /&gt;Last, but not least, the Romanian Fedora community was awesome. We got along really well and had a lot of fun. We made some really nasty videos with the fedora sign that I was going to post, but I changed my mind when I actually looked at them :), you can look at nicubunu&amp;#8217;s pictures, though.&lt;br /&gt;miscellaneous&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added 3 more O&amp;#8217;Reilly books to my I hope I&amp;#8217;ll read them this summer reading list: Beautiful Code, Masterminds of Programming and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SQL&lt;/span&gt; and the Relational Theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This conference and the people I talked to really influenced me I think, career-wise. I got a lot of motivation and a great yearning to sometime be able to work with people such as the ones I met there. I&amp;#8217;ll probably slip into a bit of a depression now that the event is over and I&amp;#8217;m going back to real life and ignorant school people. That&amp;#8217;ll hopefully be over in less than two weeks and I&amp;#8217;ll have time to work work work == fun fun fun for the Fedora Project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is I&amp;#8217;m going to FUDCon Berlin with Nicu. I hope to meet a lot of cool fedorians there aswell.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2009 00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fedora Business Cards</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/fedora-business-cards</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;A few days ago, me and a few friends from Fedora Romania decided we&amp;#8217;d like some fedora business cards for the upcoming eLiberatica conference. &lt;a href="http://ianweller.org"&gt;Ian Weller&lt;/a&gt; had already developed an official &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Business_cards"&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; and even created a cool python generator script and packaged it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, however, was that it only supported US-style business cards which are a bit smaller than the Romanian/Central European ones. Live and learnâ&amp;euro;Ś It seems that there are a lot of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Business_cards#Dimensions"&gt;different sizes&lt;/a&gt; actually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I got my hacking hat and dived in. The code was quite nice to look at and easy to understand. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; in the svg templates is quite easy to hack, too. Especially when using tools like python&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://docs.python.org/library/xml.dom.minidom.html"&gt;minidom&lt;/a&gt; . It makes working with python and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; taste like javascript dom manipulation which is quite nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything went smooth, I renamed a few tags, made some modifiable (for height and width), but then I had to make the blue strip on the right of the front of the business card extendable1 . There is no way in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt; to align an element to the right so I spent about an hour coming up with a sweet solution. Instead of having a big white background on which I would apply the blue band, I made a big blue background and made the white background just a little narrower. Because the white background was on top of the blue one, it could get aligned to the left (x=0, y=0 in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;XML&lt;/span&gt;) and cover just the part that needed to be white, and left a blue band at the right. Problem solved. Hoo-grah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;m waiting for an answer to the patch that I sent to bugzilla. Hopefully it&amp;#8217;ll be accepted and will be available in Fedora, soon, so that others may enjoy and cherish the coolness that it be!&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>GSOC - it begins...</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/GSOC-it-begins</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;My Fedora proposal got accepted to this year&amp;#8217;s Google Summer of Code Program. You can look at a short abstract &lt;a href="http://socghop.appspot.com/student_project/show/google/gsoc2009/redhat/t124024691190"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; . Now I&amp;#8217;m going to try to explain what this project is about and what I did to prepare for being accepted, hopefully without going mad about how happy I am about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started work on the Fedora Project almost a year ago. One day I popped on the mailing list and then on the irc channel of the infrastructure team and asked for something to do. Luckily, Toshio Kuratomi was on the watch and after giving me a short tour of the various projects he could help me get familiar with, I picked the package database. Most of the work I&amp;#8217;ve done so far is in the &lt;a href="https://admin.fedoraproject.org/pkgdb/"&gt;pkgdb&lt;/a&gt; (the search capability is the most obvious thing I worked on). The overview on the front page describes it quite well; it&amp;#8217;s got package information and it&amp;#8217;s aimed at package developers. It&amp;#8217;s not a very famous part of the fedora project websites, certainly not as famous as something like packages.ubuntu.com is for ubuntu. But that&amp;#8217;s not what it was intended for, even if that&amp;#8217;s what attracted me to the project at first. I liked the exposure of such a website, but also the fact that, at the time, it was easier for me to understand what it did and how it worked :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of making the package database more user-friendly as opposed to developer-centric wasn&amp;#8217;t a new one. Toshio, the main developer had been thinking about it for a long time, but I guess it never really became a priority. The idea had also been &lt;a href="http://fedoraproject.org/wiki/SummerCoding/2008/Ideas#Package_WebUI"&gt;proposed&lt;/a&gt; for last year&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSOC&lt;/span&gt;, but it hadn&amp;#8217;t been accepted (this scared me a bit when I found out). I picked this idea on a whim when I told Toshio I wanted to participate in this year&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSOC&lt;/span&gt; on pkgdb and he asked me what exactly I wanted to do. I wasn&amp;#8217;t expecting the question, so I answered with the first thing that came to mind. Looking back, I think it was a good choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my involvement with the Fedora Project owes a lot to the best possible person who could have become my mentor for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSOC&lt;/span&gt;. The Infrastructure Team is a great one to work with, and the Fedora contributor community is made up of a lot of smart, fun and selfless people. I say this after having spent a lot of time lurking the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IRC&lt;/span&gt; channels, the various mailing lists, the planet etc. and to a somewhat lesser extent interacting with other contributors. However, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have continued contributing if it weren&amp;#8217;t for the continuous support and guidance of Toshio. I probably wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been able to participate in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSOC&lt;/span&gt; without the many discussions (starting in February) with Toshio about the proposal and the support when explaining the idea to other community members. Having said that, I think that being familiar with the pkgdb also helped a lot with writing the proposal. I didn&amp;#8217;t have to waste time on getting to know the code, the community, the devs as I would have if I had written a proposal for a different project. I also had a fair idea of what would constitute a good proposal and a rough idea about how it could be implemented. I think this helped with my credibility in the eyes of the mentors who ranked my proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was never convinced I would get a spot on Fedora &amp; JBoss&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://socghop.appspot.com/org/home/google/gsoc2009/redhat"&gt;accepted proposal&amp;#8217;s list&lt;/a&gt; , but it was is a great thing to dream of. The butterflies in my stomach were killing me at the end of the waiting period, especially since it had lasted for more than 2 months. I now have a summer to work full time on my hobby :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the summer, the fedora community will hopefully have a package database with package versions, size, dependencies, rss feeds, tagging, package reviews etc. There&amp;#8217;s even a detailed &lt;a href="https://fedorahosted.org/packagedb/wiki/EndUserUI"&gt;schedule&lt;/a&gt; from my proposal you can drool on if you&amp;#8217;re so inclined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And hello, fedora planet! Sorry for being late.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2009 23:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
