<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="1.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Revolution blahg</title>
        <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/</link>
        <description>mapleoin's rambling blahg</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 19:08:56 +0300</pubDate>
        <generator>pyBlee!</generator>
        <item>
            <title>The Productive Programmer</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/productive-programmer-review</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;Today I read &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0596519788?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpmapleoinb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0596519788"&gt;The Productive Programmer&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve already got a bunch of books piled up and waiting to be read, some of which I&amp;#8217;ve reached the middle of and some of which I&amp;#8217;ve read only the introduction to. I was bored today and this looked like an easy read that I could drop at any time. It is an easy read, but the fact is, it&amp;#8217;s very catchy. It draws you in and doesn&amp;#8217;t want to be let go. It&amp;#8217;s a great way to spend half a day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could have been another one of those &amp;#8220;94 things you need to know&amp;#8221; books, but I think this title is way better. The tips are divided into 2 big sections and a few separate chapters within each one, giving the book some structure. One of the strange things about it is that its advice spans across 3 different platforms (*nix, OS X and Windows) and they&amp;#8217;re all mingled together in the same chapter. I was put off by this at first, but after I&amp;#8217;d gotten into the book a bit I realized that it is, in fact, a good idea. The whole theme of the book is programmer productivity and the reason it has this title and not a cheesy title with numbers like &amp;#8220;94.3 productivity tips for programmers&amp;#8221; is that the tips aren&amp;#8217;t what&amp;#8217;s important. The book is there to hit people in the head with and open their minds. You aren&amp;#8217;t supposed to just use the tips provided, that&amp;#8217;s unimportant. What&amp;#8217;s important is that you have a shock and realize that you&amp;#8217;ve been the wrong kind of lazy as a programmer. You&amp;#8217;ve stopped automating, you&amp;#8217;ve become a machine; in the author&amp;#8217;s own words, computers have started &amp;#8220;getting together late at night to make fun of their users&amp;#8221;. As soon as I realized what this book was really about, I started reading the Windows tips as well. I also stopped a few times to look in my distro&amp;#8217;s repository for tools that I had known of, but never used before, only now understanding their true purpose. There are many applications that seem just trendy at first, until you realize that even a small productivity boost is a big productivity boost. (Go check out &lt;i&gt;gnome-do&lt;/i&gt; , I&amp;#8217;d heard about it years ago, but never tried it until now).&lt;br /&gt;The book contains tips ranging from application launchers, Firefox&amp;#8217;s magic address bar, bash scripting commands to office productivity tips for killing distractions. Once again, the mindset is important, not the tips themselves. The big take-away from this book is beginning to constantly judge everything you do as a programmer. This isn&amp;#8217;t new advice (at least for those who have read &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/020161622X?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpmapleoinb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=020161622X"&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221;, which by the way is mentioned several times in this book), but I find it&amp;#8217;s better emphasized in this book. At one point in the book, the author explains how it took his team one hour to devise a Ruby script to automate some simple task that would&amp;#8217;ve required 10 minutes if done manually and finally only needed doing 5 times. One could say there was a loss in productivity, but as the author points out, one would be wrong. Those 50 minutes would&amp;#8217;ve been spent with the brain turned off, whereas the hour writing the script was spent &lt;i&gt;learning&lt;/i&gt;, focusing, practicing, gaining knowledge that can later be used on a different project. Some of us would probably have gotten bored in those 50 minutes and fallen into procrastination. That doesn&amp;#8217;t happen when you&amp;#8217;ve got a complex problem to solve.&lt;br /&gt;That was the first part of the book, &lt;i&gt;Mechanics&lt;/i&gt;. The second part, &lt;i&gt;Practice&lt;/i&gt; is a bit harder to read, as it&amp;#8217;s not just disparaged tips on very different applications. They&amp;#8217;re quite two separate books actually. The majority of the examples in Part IIare java (they&amp;#8217;re mostly readable even for someone who doesn&amp;#8217;t speak the exact dialect of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOP&lt;/span&gt; that java uses) and this part is mostly about software &lt;i&gt;construction&lt;/i&gt; as &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/0735619670?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=httpmapleoinb-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0735619670"&gt;Steve McConnell&lt;/a&gt; would say, but it&amp;#8217;s also about Java. I learned a new acronym: &lt;acronym title="You Ain’t Gonna Need It"&gt;YAGNI&lt;/acronym&gt; which basically means that thinking ahead is bad. This is probably one of the advices that I feel the least guilty about, but which I sometime observe in people around me. Never program a feature you don&amp;#8217;t urgently have a need for.&lt;br /&gt;One of the good points of this book is the originality with which the ideas are expressed. Most of these ideas aren&amp;#8217;t new, especially to anyone who&amp;#8217;s read other software engineering books. The text is spiced up with little narratives of different adventures from the author&amp;#8217;s experience as a consultant and there is also an &lt;i&gt;Ancient Philosophers&lt;/i&gt; chapter and an explanation of the PacMan game&amp;#8217;s way of functioning (although I didn&amp;#8217;t understand how that&amp;#8217;s supposed to make the game less enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
