<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="1.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Revolution blahg</title>
        <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/</link>
        <description>mapleoin's rambling blahg</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2010 19:08:56 +0300</pubDate>
        <generator>pyBlee!</generator>
        <item>
            <title>The late Fedora Summer coder</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/the-late-fedora-summer-coder</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (Oin Maple)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;I started my &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Summer_Coding_2010"&gt;Fedora Summer Coding&lt;/a&gt; last week. Although most people started almost two months ago, I chose (and was allowed to &amp;#8211; Yay, &lt;acronym title="Fedora Summer Coding"&gt;FSC&lt;/acronym&gt;!) a different schedule because I just finished college last week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer I&amp;#8217;ll be working on a new project for Fedora &amp;#8211; &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Category:Copr"&gt;Copr&lt;/a&gt;. Fedora Copr will allow any Fedorian to have their own package repository with packages built and hosted by &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Infrastructure"&gt;Fedora&amp;#8217;s Infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;. My mentor this summer will be &lt;a href="http://anonbadger.wordpress.com/"&gt;Toshio&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve always enjoyed working with him and this summer will be no different. &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Summer_Coding_2010_proposal_-_Copr_TG_app"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is my actual &lt;acronym title="Fedora Summer Coding"&gt;FSC&lt;/acronym&gt; proposal. Although the things written in that proposal are turning out to be a bit inaccurate, it&amp;#8217;s still a good bird&amp;#8217;s eye view of what I&amp;#8217;m going to do this summer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So about the first week. Things started really slow. I did a lot of orientation, certainly more than I thought I would. I hadn&amp;#8217;t used TurboGears2 before, though I had worked with TurboGears 1.x on &lt;a href="https://admin.fedoraproject.org/pkgdb"&gt;Fedora&amp;#8217;s pkgdb&lt;/a&gt;. When I started out I had only a TG2 automatically generated skeleton app &amp;#8211; well it&amp;#8217;s mostly the same now, though at least I now know a lot more about what&amp;#8217;s in there. The fact that I had to start it up myself meant I had to learn a lot of things about TG2 that I would&amp;#8217;ve normally just copied from other parts of a fully-functional project. And that was a great experience. In a way it&amp;#8217;s fulfilling to be able to &lt;em&gt;pioneer&lt;/em&gt; things in this way ;). I&amp;#8217;m trying to only ask my mentor questions about designing the actual app and solve my &amp;#8220;How do I &amp;#8230; in TurboGears/Python?&amp;#8221; questions elsewhere. My mentor has always given me a lot of independence when working on things and that feels really good, though at times I feel inexperienced. There&amp;#8217;s the thought that the project I&amp;#8217;m working on will be used by a lot of technical users and I&amp;#8217;m really not sure what my decisions&amp;#8217; impact will be on the whole project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m mostly on time with my &lt;a href="https://fedoraproject.org/wiki/Summer_Coding_2010_proposal_-_Copr_TG_app#Timeline"&gt;mock-up schedule&lt;/a&gt; because I had set the first week for orienteering. I also wrote the DB schema for Coprs, though that was on the second week. That doesn&amp;#8217;t mean I&amp;#8217;m ahead of schedule however, because I&amp;#8217;ll probably have a lot to work on the Copr controllers, and a lot of documenting and designing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m proud that I setup testing after a day of wading through the scattered documentation of TurboGears2 testing. There&amp;#8217;s mostly no documentation on testing on the &lt;a href="http://www.turbogears.org/2.0/docs/toc.html"&gt;TurboGears2.0 docs website&lt;/a&gt;. So I went to the &lt;a href="http://somethingaboutorange.com/mrl/projects/nose/0.11.2/"&gt;python nose&lt;/a&gt; webpage. But they don&amp;#8217;t have any info on the TurboGears2 web helpers which I needed to use. So I went to &lt;a href="http://pylonsbook.com/en/1.1/testing.html"&gt;pylonshq docs about testing&lt;/a&gt;, but they use a slightly different syntax because they&amp;#8217;re using paste.fixture. I finally found the &lt;a href="http://turbogears.org/2.1/docs/main/Testing/index.html"&gt;TurboGears2.1 testing docs&lt;/a&gt; which was what I really needed. It turns out that TurboGears 2.x uses &lt;a href="http://pythonpaste.org/webtest/"&gt;WebTest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now I have testing. My project is not supposed to have any web interface at this point, so writing tests is the easiest way to prove that things are actually working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This next week I&amp;#8217;ll probably get some work done on Copr controllers. Implementing the ability to &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CRUD&lt;/span&gt; Coprs and Repos.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 14:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
