<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="1.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Revolution blahg</title>
        <link>http://mapleoin.eu/</link>
        <description>mapleoin's rambling blahg</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 12:19:21 +0300</pubDate>
        <generator>pyBlee!</generator>
        <item>
            <title>Living with free music for a year</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.eu/perma/freemusic</link>
            <author>mapleoin@lavabit.ro (mapleoin)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been about a year and a half since I&amp;#8217;ve decided to stop pirating music. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason for me having the courage to do this is because I had found &lt;a href="http://jamendo.com"&gt;Jamendo&lt;/a&gt;. Jamendo is a place for artists to post their &lt;strong&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/strong&gt; licensed work and for anyone else to download or stream free of charge. Armed with this and my 20 CD collection, I decided to delete all my previous music collection and start anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me give you some background on this. My music collection was medium-sized before. As big as any other adolescent&amp;#8217;s. I AM an audiophile, having always listened to a wide range of music, many hours a day and having played piano when I was little and guitar now. I have never actually created any music however. So I&amp;#8217;m probably just your average, bit of an audiophile, Joe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was: download everything I liked from jamendo and then buy some 1-2 CDs/month. I kept to it. I also created a new &lt;a href="http://www.last.fm/user/fuhur"&gt;last.fm profile&lt;/a&gt; to track my listening habits and to supplement them with their streaming feature. My motivation was to keep everything legal and ogg. The same way I have no pirated software on my computer I could have no pirated music. The world would be a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the glory days, I used to download 10 albums a day from jamendo. I generally kept them for 2-3 weeks so I could listen to them at least twice and then deleted what I didn&amp;#8217;t like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found some amazing artists I could never have found in the mainstream like &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/the.octave.band"&gt;The Octave Band&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/Tom_Fahy"&gt;Tom Fahy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/revolutionvoid"&gt;Revolution Void&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/noise.sound.nation"&gt;Noise sound nation&lt;/a&gt; . I also found some that could&amp;#8217;ve made it to the mainstream, but didn&amp;#8217;t: &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/officialwhiteroom"&gt;WhiteRoom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/whiteyes"&gt;Whiteyes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/eternaltango"&gt;Eternal Tango&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/tryad"&gt;try^d&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/contreband"&gt;Contreband&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.jamendo.com/en/artist/hype"&gt;HYPE&lt;/a&gt; etc. There was a lot of bad music and a lot of experiments. But hey! There&amp;#8217;s a lot of bad music in the mainstream, too, although not as much experiments because that&amp;#8217;s not what mainstream is for. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;#8217;t complain about the quality of the music, but I can complain about the quality of the audio files on the site and the site itself which is probably the most-failed-startup-that-could&amp;#8217;ve-been-big in existence. Jamendo has oggs, but you can only get them via bittorrent and nowadays they don&amp;#8217;t work most of the time. The website is a nightmare as far as usability is concerned and the design is from the 90s. Jamendo has a lot of potential and I heard it&amp;#8217;s big in France, but I can&amp;#8217;t see what&amp;#8217;s stopping them from being big on the Web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to my experience. I had a lot of fun and I really didn&amp;#8217;t miss much of the music I had been listening to before. I could always brag to my friends and recommend them artists that they had never heard of. I could listen to awesome new sounds, some of which could be called: melancholic noise music, trance jazz, psychedelic bored music etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My legal music collection is now 12G big with 113 artists, 23 of which are ripped cds. It&amp;#8217;s all ogg. &lt;br /&gt;These days I&amp;#8217;m beginning to get bored and annoyed with jamendo&amp;#8217;s mismanagement. I haven&amp;#8217;t downloaded a new jamendo album in months and that&amp;#8217;s not because I haven&amp;#8217;t tried.&lt;br /&gt;The interest in me keeping this legal music collection just faded. I&amp;#8217;ve lost motivation. Also, there are a lot of commercial artists that sound interesting and that I can&amp;#8217;t buy locally. Music isn&amp;#8217;t like software. You can&amp;#8217;t replace an artist with another just because they&amp;#8217;re in the same genre. With software you have to get something done, regardless of the means. With music, you&amp;#8217;re not just listening to &lt;em&gt;music&lt;/em&gt;, the means is the purpose and every artist is irreplaceable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m probably going to migrate my music collection to flac files since my audiophile needs have just become more aristocratic after I bought a new hi-fi head-set. I&amp;#8217;m still going to be watching the artists I love from jamendo that no one will ever hear about. I might even go on a raid or two at the bay of pirates.&lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2009 00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
