<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="1.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Revolution blahg</title>
        <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/</link>
        <description>mapleoin's rambling blahg</description>
        <language>en</language>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 18:01:16 +0300</pubDate>
        <generator>pyBlee!</generator>
        <item>
            <title>Beginning packaging for Fedora</title>
            <link>http://mapleoin.bluepink.ro/perma/packaging-for-fedora</link>
            <author>mapleoin@bluepink.ro (mapleoin)</author>
            <description>  &lt;p&gt;With &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GSOC&lt;/span&gt; now over, which I should write a blogpost about soon, I&amp;#8217;ve taken a break from pkgdb and web programming and started developing another skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that &lt;a href="https://admin.fedoraproject.org/pkgdb/users/packages/mapleoin"&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; is empty has been bugging me for too much time, so I set out to fix it. I also wanted to find out more about the packaging process and the road of a package before it gets accepted into fedora&amp;#8217;s official repos which is a bit complex. This knowledge would also help me better understand the parts of pkgdb which packagers interact with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was not my first time trying to make a package for fedora. I think this is actually my third time. I&amp;#8217;d given up before, scared by all the different tools and scattered documentation. In a previous life, I had made some &lt;a href="http://aur.archlinux.org/"&gt;AUR&lt;/a&gt; packages, but the experience is a lot different. I&amp;#8217;m now starting to get used to all the different tools that I was scared of before, like mock and rpmlint and I can now find my way around the fedora wiki for package related information. There is a wealth of information in the wiki, but you need a lot of patience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started slow, with quite a complex application to package: &lt;a href="http://calibre.kovidgoyal.net/"&gt;Calibre&lt;/a&gt;. Having all those different distros is great when you&amp;#8217;re a packager, because you have somewhere to look for help and the Debian package of calibre helped me a lot. It took me about two days to get a somewhat acceptable version of calibre packaged, which I then posted to redhat&amp;#8217;s bugzilla. The following days I found more small apps to be packaged and it became easier and easier for me to do it. Last night for example, I was just browsing &lt;a href="http://news.ycombinator.org"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; as usual when I found a link to &lt;a href="http://developers.facebook.com/news.php?blog=1&amp;amp;story=301"&gt;facebook&amp;#8217;s opensourcing of their web server framework&lt;/a&gt; . I just rushed to the download and installation instructions page and I quickly got it packaged. I&amp;#8217;m not saying it&amp;#8217;s perfect, it probably needs a lot of improvement, but it was fun to do. It&amp;#8217;s fun to think that you&amp;#8217;re making things easier for someone and learning a lot at the same time. I now have 5 packages waiting to be reviewed and I&amp;#8217;ve found someone willing to sponsor me into the &lt;strong&gt;packager&lt;/strong&gt; group. Anyone in a package-review mood? ;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey into the packaging world has been enlightening so far and the good thing is I&amp;#8217;m just beginning. There&amp;#8217;s a whole new world to be discovered out there and also another part of the fedora community. &lt;/p&gt; </description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 10:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
